<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stan for cognitive science</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Stan for cognitive science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Books and tutorials using Stan</title>
      <link>/books-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>Books Bayesian Cognitive Modeling: A Practical Course (2014) by Michael Lee and Eric-Jan Wagenmakers. Stan code available
Doing Bayesian Data Analysis: A Tutorial with R, JAGS, and Stan (2014) by John Kruschke
Statistical rethinking: A Bayesian course with examples in R and Stan (2020) by Richard McElreath
An Introduction to Bayesian Data Analysis for Cognitive Science (in progress) by Bruno Nicenboim, Daniel Schad, and Shravan Vasishth
 Courses Handouts Mark Lai’s course handouts for PSYC 621 class</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers using Stan</title>
      <link>/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/</guid>
      <description>Papers using Stan (or brms, rstanarm)  2021   Brochhagen, T. “Brief at the Risk of Being Misunderstood: Consolidating Population- and Individual-Level Tendencies”. In: Computational Brain &amp;amp; Behavior (2021). DOI: 10.1007/s42113-021-00099-x.  2020   Abir, Y. and R. R. Hassin. “Getting to the heart of it: Multi-method exploration of nonconscious prioritization processes”. In: Consciousness and Cognition 85 (2020), p. 103005.  Avetisyan, S., S. Lago, and S. Vasishth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StanConnect 2021 - Cognitive Science and Neuroscience session</title>
      <link>/stanconnect2021-cogsci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/stanconnect2021-cogsci/</guid>
      <description>Online session of StanConnect 2021 The Cognitive Science and Neuroscience session of StanConnect 2021 will happen on November 19, 2021 5:00 pm CET (e.g., Amsterdam) / 11:00 am ET (e.g., New York). For more details about StanConnect 2021 see https://mc-stan.org/events/.
 Speakers     Speaker name Talk    Gang Chen Resolving the multiple testing issue in neuroimaging through Bayesian multilevel modeling  Kendal Foster and Henrik Singmann Implementation of the Diffusion Decision Model with Across-Trial Variability in the Drift Rate  Mike Lawrence It’s complicated: Some observations on the nuanced constraints of the multivariate normal in high dimensions  Jan Göttmann Using computational modeling parameters to measure working memory processes     Tentative schedule (times in ET) of each event:  11am - 11:15am: Introduction to the Event by SGB representative, Introduction to theme by Session Chair 11:15am - 1:15pm: four 30-minute talks - 20 minute presentation + 10 minute Q&amp;amp;A.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
